<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Showcases on Tarant</title>
    <link>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Showcases on Tarant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Actors playing Ping Pong</title>
      <link>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/ping-pong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/ping-pong/</guid>
      <description>This example shows how actors can call each other without blocking themselves.
Features used  Async Actors: Async actors with promises are already part of Tarant. Any method that is marked as async will be handled asynchronously and non-blocking by Tarant, and messages are guaranteed to be processed in order.  Live Example See the Pen tarant ping pong example by Kevin Mas Ruiz (@kmruiz) on CodePen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub Sub for Actors</title>
      <link>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/pub-sub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/pub-sub/</guid>
      <description>This example demonstrates how Actors process messages independently. When you press the +1 button, you will see how there are two counters, one that updates fast, and one that updates slower.
Load is simulated using a sleep function with a setTimeout.
Features used  Topics: Topics encapsulate communication between actors in a fan out basis. Each actor subscribed to a topic will eventually receive messages in guaranteed order. In this specific use case, the +1 button is sending, each time the user clicks on it, a message through a topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Operations</title>
      <link>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/scheduleds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarantx.github.io/showcases/scheduleds/</guid>
      <description>This example shows how actors can schedule the execution of messages dynamically.
Features used  Scheduleds: Scheduleds are handled by actors, are non-blocking and support asynchronous methods.  Live Example See the Pen tarant scheduleds example by Kevin Mas Ruiz (@kmruiz) on CodePen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>